# Mario Roman

# Engineering Manager | Fintech Leader | High-Impact Teams | Integrating AI to Accelerate Product Delivery

📞 +54-(911)-5516-4711 @ mario.roman@gmail.com 🔗 <u>linkedin.com</u> 🗣 Buenos Aires, Argentina



#### SUMMARY

Director of Engineering at Stori with 25+ years of experience delivering large-scale technical systems. I lead the development of products that expand credit and deposit access, optimize conversion, and improve customer operations. Passionate about innovation, I'm currently focused on integrating AI LLMs, RAG, and AI agents-into engineering workflows to accelerate delivery and enhance customer experiences. MSc in Computer Science from Universidad de Buenos Aires.

#### EXPERIENCE

## **Director of Engineering**

Stori 04/2023 - Present CDMX, México

- Directed multiple business units with a combined team of 93 direct and indirect reports, overseeing cross-functional operations and strategic initiatives.
- Led the technical vision and execution of new onboarding process designed to enhance credit and deposit accessibility and optimize conversion. Increasing deposit accounts with 135k new accounts in a mont (90% of the previous flows achieved in an entire year). Improving credit conversion speed by 45% (84% more time-efficient than previous flows). Reducing time from sign-up to credit approval, improving same-day acceptance rates by ~20% points over BAU.
- Developed new game-changer features for a native app Enabling the product team to launch new functionalities without a new native version release, improving delivery speed from 3 weeks to days. Rapid integration of third-party services (AliExpress, Shein) from weeks to hours.
- Piloted an MVP using LLMs and Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) to create Alpowered customer service bots, laying the groundwork for scalable, automated support.
- · Led a transition from mobile native technologies to platform-agnostic development by leveraging AI agents and Cursor to automate code migratio

# **Director Of Engineering**

Konfío 04/2022 - 04/2023 CDMX, México

- Led the Payments Technical Platform, overseeing a team of approximately 45 professionals (direct and indirect reports), and was responsible for defining the strategic roadmap and budget plans.
- Improved Payments Services Availability by 20% and reduced response time by 50%.
- Launched Custom Customer Rate to lower onboarding churn rates.
- Introduced Automated Money Disbursement, reducing fund availability to <24 hours.
- Contributed to obtaining PCI Compliance Certification.
- Led migration from a monolithic to microservices/event-driven architecture.

### **Software Engineering Manager**

Mercado Pago 01/2000 - 04/2022 Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Launched Salary Portability in Brazil, Mercado Pago's first payroll product.
- Delivered large-scale technical systems, including Users Feed, handling 318K RPM writes, 250K RPM reads, and 251TB storage.
- Developed a Well-Being financial product to enhance user savings and investment capabilities

### **Head Of Technology**

Radio Mitre MdP 08/2017 - 12/2019 Buenos Aires, Argentina

• Led a digital transformation initiative for Argentina's top radio station. Launched CMS Arc Publishing, boosting website traffic by 30%.. Introduced advertising tools, increasing radio revenue by 15%.

# **Software Engineering Manager**

Keenvil 06/2016 - 08/2017 Buenos Aires, Argentina

• Led cross-functional teams to design and build innovative software solutions.

#### **Technical Director**

Globant 2007 - 2014 Buenos Aires, Argentina

- · Technical Director at Anheuser-Busch InBev
- Technical Director at M-GO (Technicolor & DreamWorks Joint Venture)
- · Technical Leader at The Walt Disney Company, Google, and OSG Ship Management

**EDUCATION** 

## Master of Science (MS), Computer Science

Universidad de Buenos Aires 07/1997 - 10/2004 Buenos Aires, Argentina

# Management Integral de Negocios **Digitales**

Univeridad de San Andrés

03/2019 - 10/2019 Buenos Aires, Argentina

LANGUAGES

**English** 

Proficient

Spanish

Native

**SKILLS** 

Al Enthusiast

**Engineer Leadership & Team Scaling** 

**Data Driven Decision Making** 

**Fintech Product Strategy** 

Cloud & Microservices Architecture (AWS)

Mentorship

**Team Development** 

Agile Methodologies & Process Optimization

Powered by Enhancy